this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software digital ocean is the easiest
cloud platform to deploy manage and
scale applications of any size we're
moving infrastructure friction and
providing predictability so developers
and their teams can deploy faster and
focus on building software that
customers love with thousands of
in-depth tutorials in an active
community we provide the support you
need digitalocean stands out of the
crowd due to its simplicity and high
performance with no billing surprises
try digitalocean for free by getting a
one hundred dollar infrastructure credit
at doco / SC radio so welcome everyone
to the software engineering radio today
my name is Kim Carter I'll be your host
for the day and today we've got Natalie
Silvana which is guest nearly is a
security engineer on the Google project
zero team who reviews heavily used our
software for security problems nearly
has discovered over 100 vulnerabilities
and browsers mobile devices and security
software
welcome to the show Natalie great thanks
so much for inviting me so we've had
shows on application security with Zane
Leakey that was show number 309 and
we've had network security now with her
une mère that was show number 302 today
we're going to be discussing a tech
surface reduction so I'm just gonna
start off with some pretty basic
questions
can you explain nearly what a tech
surface actually is every application
every piece of software has an attack
surface this is what ever an attacker
can manipulate the api's of your web
application or the files that your file
format parser processes anything that an
attacker can use and find bugs in is
attack surface yes I'm not just software
well it it usually is software
but when we talk about an attack surface
it's really the features of the software
and in particular the ones that are
available to an attacker in a way that
is useful to give an example let's say
you have a web application that also
processes some local files on the server
it runs on the remote stuff that an
attacker can reach is much more
concerning attack surface then say the
local stuff why is that well you have to
think about it from the attackers
perspective if you're an attacker
usually you want to access data on a
system or do something else unauthorized
on a system and depending on your
vantage point you have different options
so if you think about software that's
accessible over the Internet
there are tons and tons of attackers on
the internet that could access it and
use it to do something bad so that's
something to be concerned about and then
sometimes there are situations in
software where if you think about who
can change certain input it's not
someone who would want access to the
system or it's someone who already has
access to the system so that's why it's
not a concern so if we are to reduce
attack surface now we need to be able to
measure it how would you go about
quantifying the attack surface before
and after defects have been found and
fixed it was very difficult to do and
there's no metric where you can say like
I have five attack surface or something
like that but I think I'm what what is
the most important is just understanding
the attack surface you have actually
going through your software or your
application whatever you're working on
and make sure you understand every
feature that you have and how it can be
accessed so how does your fate modeling
approach take into consideration the
severity as well as the number of
defects personally I don't do a lot of
threat modeling my team we're mostly
interested in finding bugs that are used
by malicious attackers we call them
zero-day bugs and so we pick our targets
based on how commonly zero-day
vulnerabilities show up in a piece of
software
and how serious the problems are yeah
okay so so I'm working on a project for
example I've measured a my attack
surface I've done some fit modeling and
I found and fixed some defects and then
I've done some more threat modeling so
I've I've measured again and the attack
surface is now ten percent smaller
there's my project now ten percent more
secure maybe these things are always
difficult to measure but I think it's
that's usually not the case because
usually some parts of software are far
more prone to threats than other parts
of software and this is really what I'm
talking about quite often what I'm
talking about attack surface reduction
because every feature that software has
is useful for something to user is
hopefully and then it has a risk to
users and it's kind of important that
those are in line if you have a feature
that is not used very often but is very
high risk and as tons of defects in it
and that sort of thing you know that's
something you need to get rid of
meanwhile sometimes things can be high
risk but if they're very useful then
that's not a feasible thing to do
so yeah just you know removing 10% of
your code there's no guarantee that
that's going to remove 10% of your
problems almost everyone's code base
they probably have one thing they could
remove that would reduce far more
problems than the percentage of code it
makes up yeah so you mentioned in your
smallest beautiful talk that we should
base features on user need and we should
track features use in beta or production
and not be willing and able to disable
features so I think this is pretty good
advice is this assuming we have zero
users consuming the specific feature no
it's not and it really depends where you
are in the dev process um which is part
of why I went around giving that talk
because you know once users are using a
feature it becomes a lot more difficult
to remove or even a change the attack
surface of so of course the easiest
thing is before a feature comes out to
think about whether it's useful to users
and specifically think about the risk of
poses and whether maybe there is
other ways to provide that benefit with
without having the same risk and then
once you get into the point where you
have the feature in that's where maybe
you don't have as many options and you
can remove a feature if users are still
using it
there's several several examples
situations where vendors have done that
for example Microsoft has disabled
several features for example certain
parsers in their document programs but
that's always going to turn off a
certain number of users so that's
something which it's often only possible
if something is really obsolete and
they're an auditor that much usage you
also mentioned that all code has a risk
and they're adding a feature as a
trade-off
I usually go but further than this and I
say that all features are trade-offs
including physical people VPS as
networks cloud mobile and IOT and we
need to be considering the attack
surface of everything can you apply the
previous question in answer to all of
these areas and if so yeah yeah I'm not
sure how much guidance I can provide on
that because I mostly look at software
but I think it is true that when you add
a feature to software you need to
consider the full cost of it so I always
have security on my brain so I'm
thinking about the security cost but it
is true about you know people hardware
everything else every feature has a cost
and it's fairly common for people not to
consider the full cost of doing things
before they do it actually one of the
examples I give in my talk is branching
and different types of build systems
it's fairly common for companies to
start creating new versions of software
or branching or creating new SKUs if
it's a physical product without fully
understanding the cost including the
security cost and then that can lead to
problems later when they discover they
have to push updates to everything yeah
yeah we're going to get into branching
in it something a little bit later on
too so we're just going to move into a
small section on odd software engineers
in their current state in terms of a
tech service
can you explain here you are
significantly reducing the number of
people harmed by targeted attacks when
any number of the bags that the project
zero
team for example identifies appear to be
completely swamped by the contingent lot
continual onslaught that developers
continue to be creating in I mean just
about everything produced yeah well they
certainly hope that that is not the case
this is true that some products do have
the problem where there are certain
components where the rate at which they
add bugs is so fast that right it
becomes difficult to fix them because
new bugs are just being added but I
would hope that a lot of the stuff we
look at is mature enough that this isn't
the case and I think we should see an
evidence of this in that and when we
found security bugs sometimes other
people I'm even malicious attackers are
discovered to be using the same bugs and
we call that bug collision which means
that we're causing a bug that's actively
being used to be fixed and this happens
enough that we do think that we are
finding the same bugs as attackers and
getting them fixed um does have an
impact yeah yeah I think it's because
you're focusing on the most heavily used
software I would say that would be
correct yeah that's definitely true
since the software we look at is so
heavily used it bugs in it are fairly
virus and that's why this approach is
useful um so there was a post on the NPM
blog recently called attitudes to
security in the JavaScript community so
in this post
now there was 87 percent of our
respondents said they were concerned
with the security of the code they wrote
themselves compared to only 77 percent
saying the same about the open source
libraries that they were consuming this
to me sounds like a wake-up call for the
security community has that we've been
waiting for for years and it's actually
starting to happen what are your
thoughts on these statistics do they see
unrealistic and are you noticing a
similar trend and developers taking
security more seriously I think that's
true
most developers I do meet are fairly
concerned about security and I think
that's really a positive thing but I
think being concerned about security
isn't enough the companies that develop
software need to make sure that they're
giving developers adequate resources to
develop secure software and that
everyone's making it a priority so I
have noticed especially when giving this
attack surface talk that there sometimes
is a bit of a difference between what
developers want to do and what they end
up doing considering the realities of
the software they develop but I do think
it's very positive that security is at
least on the mind of a lot of developers
what's your experience into a thoughts
on where the level of security defects
are and JavaScript compared to other
languages and their environments and
what are your thoughts on these
statistics and how we can continue to
improve them yes that's a bit of a
complicated question so when you're
talking about JavaScript security you
can mean a lot of things and when I say
I look at JavaScript security I'm
looking at the security of JavaScript
engines so this is you know you visit a
web page using Chrome or edge or Safari
and then that web page causes memory
corruption in the browser and then the
browser can execute malicious code on
your system so most of that code is
actually written in C++ although some of
it is written in JavaScript these days I
mean while there is the other side of
this which is vulnerabilities in code
that is actually written in JavaScript
and I would say we see less of these
publicly and I think there's two reasons
one just because of the nature of where
JavaScript is used it's less likely
these end up getting known publicly
because people just fix their own
website and I think there's also more
fragmentation more individual web pages
that are small that used to have a
script so my suspicion is there probably
are a lot of problems there we just
don't hear as much about them yeah-yo
you're more focused on the on the most
heavily used stuff anyway right yeah how
do we go about our considering the
security impact of features at
design-time
we need a Red Team me as part of the
development team to help drive out
defects before we introduce them well I
think it's a good idea to have someone
with security experience involved in the
design of everything because there are
things you can do at every stage of
design to help secure things so to start
off even when you're thinking about
creating a new product things like you
know how you split up the components
what language you write it in and that
sort of thing can have an impact on
security and also you can start thinking
about if there's a really high risk
component like a parser or something how
you can reduce its privileges reduce its
attack surface and make it less
accessible to attackers so I think
that's a important thing to do as soon
as you're starting to think about
features and then as time goes on it's a
good idea to actually have a red team or
other team look at the code and actually
see if reality matches the way you
design the software and see if there's
any defects there so you mentioned in
your smallest beautiful talk again that
using the same code for multiple
purposes I can expose it to new and
unnecessary attack vectors I think this
is true code sharings sort of a thing
that the development community has been
trying to sort of do more of for quite a
long time sort of like the high high
Fannin on pieces of code so what are
your thoughts on rather than telling
developers not to reuse code we should
be trying to help them create more
secure pieces of code that can be
consumed yes so the consequences of code
sharing are complex so the specific
example I gave in the smallest beautiful
talk is some vulnerabilities I found in
a Samsung image decoder and what
happened there is you load the images
and then they corrupt memory and then
that that can lead to code execution and
the situation was if you say loaded them
in the gallery this would happen the
problem was the place where this
decoding happened it was in a library
called Q JPEG which we looked into and
it turned out that this was actually
only used for one thing on the device
which was
you start up your Samsung device and it
sings and it has the carrier logo on it
and that sort of thing this image
decoder is used to process that image
but it's not used for anything else but
the way they added it to the Android
image subsystem was they just plunked it
in so that this image decoder was
available everywhere including over the
Internet so that's a situation where
code was blindly reused and ended up
adding a necessary attack surface
because no one should ever be using this
image decoder other than loading a
splash screen but I yeah but I
understand what you're saying
I'm not against code reuse at all and I
think there is a huge security benefit
to code reuse in general in that code
becomes more mature but I think the
lesson here is just not to plug-and-play
to you need to understand what the
shared code does and make sure that
you're adding in the smallest amount you
need and it's appropriate for the use
you're intending it for so you also
mentioned that multiple copies of the
same code can be difficult to maintain
I've noticed that with microservices are
becoming more hip and this seems to be
happening more do we do you have any
advice other than pulling the common
code add undo separate into a separate
package and consuming as a library yes
like very much on your system there's a
lot of different options here I think
some of the more commonly used libraries
do have the option to turn off certain
features and that's a good idea I think
that's actually a very good sign even
when you're selecting which library to
use for a certain purpose if it has
flags you can use to limit its exposure
that's that's very good and yeah that's
a good option but it depends a lot on
what your system looks like but there's
kind of dual problems here one is if you
have too many copies of code and then
there's a vowel in it it can be really
hard to find them all and update them
but on the flip side you can have the
problem like the Samsung one so it's
just a trade off and it requires
evaluating your system and seeing what
the best options are can you tell us a
bit about the Android webview issues
where civil
avoid features contained their own
version of our web view in the bugs were
fixed in one version but not in another
yeah so I was on the Android security
team for a while a couple of years ago
and yes some vulnerabilities we saw were
related to Android web views which is
the part that loads HTML and
applications and there were issues with
both internal and external applications
bundling web views and then using
out-of-date versions they basically sync
their own copy of the code and put it
into their app and then not update it so
we ended up releasing a unified webview
so that now applications can use the
system library and there's not the same
sort of update problems so we're just
going to move into a section on
third-party code discuss this and quite
a bit of depth I'm in my own book and
the web applications chapter of holistic
in vozack for web developers for sickled
one in your talk small as beautiful
again now you mention that we should
make sure each attack service only
supports needed features and also that
we should be avoiding multiple copies of
the same library these are both concepts
that are the node package mentality
developers consume like huge numbers of
packages even and small projects often
consuming only a package to do one small
job so firstly for our listeners can you
explain what the problem is here yes I
would say that is something that worries
me a fair deal yeah so there's a couple
of problems here one is pulling in the
entire package just for one small thing
of course it depends on how you use it
but there are certain types of features
like image decoder is you can have a
huge hugely increased attack surface
even if you need it for one thing so
what happens I'm in like the node
ecosystem is that a developer will can I
consume a collection of packages say 5
10 or whatever in each of those packages
I consumes I like another package and
that might be duplicated from whether
your other dependent packages so they're
both consuming the same package but in
different places yes so it just starts
to get quite messy
yeah it does that is a
quite cause the same concern as say
having just multiple copies of the same
library on a file system because it does
seem like at the very least there is a
way to reasonably update them but I do
think it's possible to have problems
with something like node where since
you're pulling in multiple copies of a
library you think you're using only one
version but you're not you're actually
using two versions including an outdated
version and that could be a problem the
other thing about this know thing that
concerns me and it's something else that
I mentioned in my talk is that you
should do due diligence on third-party
components and make sure they're
suitable for the need and that sort of
thing and I feel that a lot of node
projects include you know so many
components that have dependencies and
their dependencies have dependencies and
it's really hard to know for sure what's
actually in a project is some pretty
good tooling around now that's starting
to mature up so we're at a point that
you would write something yourself as
opposed to I'm actually consuming a
library I think in general it's a good
idea to use libraries especially if
they're immature one for things like say
SSL or image parsing or anything that's
really security high risk it's almost
always a good idea to use a library the
only situation where I would say oh it's
probably better to write it yourself is
if there's no mature libraries for
example if you're pulling something off
of github that you think hardly anyone
uses it's a very good idea I think
either to write that yourself or make
sure that you're very heavily reviewing
that code a lot of the problems that I
see with third-party code do come from
using these very uncommon lis used
components that aren't maintained you've
also mentioned are tracking third-party
software use and having an internal
process that you use now which I've also
discussed in my previously mentioned
book can you explain how you would do
this yeah well there's lots of different
ways to do this but let me start a
little bit with kind of a nightmare
scenario that I encountered when working
on project zero tavis Ormandy and
we're looking at a fire eye appliance
called the malware protection system and
basically what this does is this go
through like all your email attachments
and that sort of thing and looks for
certain types of malware and we
discovered they were using a java
decompiler to decompile
any jar files that went over the network
interface and they used a java
decompiler called Joad which they pulled
off the internet I think without
evaluating and they used to process
these malicious files and then Tavis
contacted the developer and he said that
the C compiler actually executed the
code as it decompile zit it was
completely not suitable for this purpose
so that's a case where this is obviously
like a very bad security problem you
send someone an email and it gets
executed on this network appliance and
it's an example I'm not sure what
happened there but it seems like either
they weren't keeping good track of what
their third-party components were or
they weren't making sure they had the
same security boundaries that they
needed so I think a more mature way to
do this is to have some sort of internal
process for using a third-party
component basically more than one person
agrees to it often you'll need to have a
legal review to find out things like how
did they get security fixes how often
will you get updates that sort of thing
and make sure that that is all suitable
for what you need and then it's a good
idea then to have some tracking of
versions and vulnerabilities so that if
there is a vulnerability found and a
third-party component you can know right
away you know this is where we use this
and this is how we can fix it you're
thinking I'm like tolling as well like
in ESP which is I'm acquired by
impairments naik and and get up have
also got like a security scanning system
over there over the repos near yeah
there's quite a few solutions there and
I also know a lot of companies just use
internal scripts but basically yeah you
need something that feeds into however
your projects provide their security
update
and then someone who can monitor them
and make sure that they're actually
applying all the patches that are needed
are there tools that you would like to
see automated as part of a dev sick ops
process that you think would help the
third party code problems yeah that's
something that I wish existed I've seen
a lot of attempts to make like the
perfect tool for this and I haven't seen
something that you know I think 100% of
what's needed but I do wish that there
were tools that would make it a lot
easier to in particular track when
components need updates yep so I think
we've already got that and quite a few
different tooling solutions right yeah I
guess some what I think the problem is
is I think for commonly used ones yes
but it seems like there's always you
know one straggler that just every time
there's a vulnerability they post to
their website irregular times and
keeping up to date with stuff like that
can be difficult yeah so I'm just
thinking in terms of third-party code
are smaller packages an answer or the
answer if so um do we have the package
measurement systems capable of managing
a really small packages I mean here
would I discover a bloody work it's hard
enough and now trying to find the most
suitable package out of tin that all do
the same job right yes sir so you just
be clear here what you mean by a small
package here do you mean a small number
of users or a small amount of code so a
small amount of code I think that's
challenging and also it really depends
on what sort of kind of package manager
or method of obtaining third-party code
you use so certainly there are things
like no that use package managers but
there's also a lot of source code
repositories especially ones in C++
where you know you're not just
automatically fetching packages you're
basically using static libraries or even
syncing the code for every library and
that sort of thing has other challenges
but I feel like I don't think package
manager is really the solution here just
because basically so many projects don't
use them yeah
so so so the projects that don't use
them are they mostly compiled languages
yeah I think so I'm thinking of your
puppy is forever
slide and your smallest beautiful tool
so currently if we depend on a package
that the maintainer isn't keeping
patched we need to fork and maintain it
ourselves where do you see this ending
up yeah that's that was a funny slide so
it was actually an Android developer who
said that to me and if you look at how
packages are maintained in Android right
there's no package management it is
there's the third-party directory and
people copy stuff in there and the joke
he was making is once you cut you copy
stuff in there you know it's yours
forever and you have to take care of it
because this is another problem that
open-source projects have is they'll use
a third-party library and basically not
keep it patched and yeah not think about
the maintenance of it so this is true in
both forums that both if it is
maintained that doesn't mean it's effort
free you still have to make sure you're
getting the patches but then yeah for
every open-source project you need to
think about what you're going to do if
it gets abandoned and you know that's a
very real possibility and yeah usually
this means that either you have to
maintain it or you have to you know find
current users and maintain it as a group
or something like that yes yeah I'm
working on a reasonably sized project in
the moment and I've had to pretty much
and hear it two to three packages
because the maintainer --zz have been
unresponsive in and basically bring them
up to date and weed some bugs out and
then I submit the changes back again and
then like they've still been
unresponsive so that can be really
frustrating a do you have any ideas on
how we can get any better at that
yeah that's challenging and I think the
easiest advice is to think about this
before you select the component but
that's the easiest time to realize you
know this isn't being maintained and
maybe we should use something else but
um you know once you've passed that
point it can be challenging I guess you
could try your best to contribute but
yeah if you don't have
active maintainer that's hard and also
you should count your lucky stars that
this is an open source component it can
be even more challenging if say you use
a closed source component and they go
out of business yeah yeah what are
founders like this being like one or two
or maybe three libraries that does a
specific job I don't have the expertise
in that job so I've had to sort of bite
the bullet and just use what's available
and then like I've been unresponsive and
then I've had to actually inherit it and
basically learn how the thing works and
fixing it your data is your
organization's best asset but protecting
it can feel like your greatest liability
Ravin DB is a transactional document
database that makes securing your data
efficient and simple you don't need a
PhD to use our setup wizard in minutes
your data cluster is secured with x.509
authentication and TLS 1.2 for data on
the wire and with 256 bit encryption for
data at rest download your free
Community Edition at rave and vb.net so
the node security projects at its NSP
was acquired by n p.m. on April the 10th
this year and we've got a github which
is now providing visibility into the
dependencies of their users repositories
in alerting of known security issues if
they have a common vulnerability
exposure CVE snipe provides something
similar but they've been doing this for
much longer than I get up and I know of
many more issues like the databases
obviously much larger now what are your
thoughts on how the open source
ecosystem is progressing in terms of
creating visibility around effective
code yeah a bit that's something that I
don't know a lot about I don't spend a
lot of time in in node and other
packaged managed language but that does
sound quite promising and like I wish
there was more attention to this topic
in general have you got any thoughts on
here we can do better
and that's a good question like
something I would like is more
consistency in how projects put out
security updates because some of them
they do
you know very rigorous schedules and
that sort of thing and then there are
ones especially if they don't have
security updates very often they'll just
kind of do it randomly or put it on
their website and I think a good first
step to making this more manageable
would be for projects to more
consistently explain how they put out
their security update and it would even
be nice if say there was some sort of
API or database you could put your
updates into so people could query it I
think in ESP actually have there and
it's now part of NPM I've also noticed
that yeah there was another post
recently from NPM stating that now when
you install a package from the NPM
repository that you automatically get
told whether there are and securities in
it so that's actually part of the
package manager now which i think is
pretty good initiative yeah that's a
pretty good initiative but still this is
a much more challenging problem in the
non package manage languages especially
in native code yeah so I I guess it just
comes down to talking about it Lots and
just making people aware of it and then
eventually the people are maintaining
the packages do something about it I
think unfortunately that's the best
option just moving on to a section on a
developer workflow and your talk again
small as beautiful and you mentioned
that excessive SCU's and branching I'll
make it harder to push security updates
they can introduce bugs and can cause an
incomplete patching well I think few I
would disagree with this a well-defined
and sometimes elaborate branching scheme
is necessary for large groups of
engineers or collaborating on the same
codebase
can you define excessive in this context
yes so I think actually what I need to
define here is branching so when I'm
talking about branching I don't mean
development branching I mean
independently maintained branches I know
it's hard to avoid having lots of
development branches and well-liked they
can be error-prone it's not as bad as
when say you have
you know 10 versions of software or even
there are vendors we've worked with who
have had thousands of different branches
of software that they actually released
to different customers and that's what I
think the biggest concern is the ones
that basically having a very large
number of release branches is really
what causes most problems for sure
can you talk a bit about the CVE 20 1705
to 8 that's the merger and the Android
and reducing aslr but what happened with
this and what were the issues that we
learned this was a fairly surprising bug
basically a SLR is address space layout
randomization it's a security feature in
most devices it basically means that
memory is allocated at different
addresses every time you start an
application or start the device and that
make certain memory corruption
vulnerabilities more difficult to
exploit and anyhow when Android 7.0 was
released the Android team got a bug
report that a SLR did not have the right
amount of entropy memory allocations
were not as random as they should be and
they looked into this bug report and
found that basically high entropy a SLR
had been disabled on this release of
Android and they dug a bit deeper and it
turned out that Qualcomm had released a
fix and to start off Qualcomm has a lot
of branches of their varying software
and then the fixes and all of these
branches had to be merged into Android
which also has an extremely large number
of branches and in these many updates
that had to be made there was one error
made which was this specific branch
which was Android 7.0 and this ended up
on defining a flag that enabled the SLR
so this is just an example of
maintaining lots of branches is an
extremely error-prone process and I feel
like no matter how well you try to do it
if you're trying to merge something into
dozens of branches you're gonna mess up
eventually yes so I think you're talking
about orphaned
ranchers are semantically right rather
than like feature branches is it correct
these are still branches that are in use
for different versions of Android it's
just there's a lot of them they're not
feature branches right yeah like these
these are really stretches so if you go
to say OSP you can download you know
Android eight or Android seven or
Android five and usually a two or three
of these are being maintained at
different times before the show you
mentioned you also had some anonymized
examples of bugs
one was we have ended a failed picture
security issue due to a complex
branching and build system in the
patches were also taking a long time due
to this can you talk a little bit about
that sure so this is anonymous vendor
number one and what they did is they
forgot to patch a bug and they told us
they'd patched the bug and then it
turned out they hadn't and we asked what
happened and they said that they have a
lot of different software branches and
they also have a lot of different
physical devices they make but the usage
of them is very diverse so you know
there are things that have you know
millions of users and then there's
things that have thousands of users and
they're all on this big build three and
anyhow what happened is they put in this
fix to this issue and then it has to
basically merge through that entire tree
into every product and then they told us
they got the fix in and then like a day
or so later one of the builds breaks and
they have to pull the whole thing out
and then there was a communication error
where their engineering team forgot to
tell the team that was communicating
with us and I mean that sort of thing
happens but I think the other more
important thing that I learned from this
is that this build system was basically
delaying patches for months you know
every time they had this problem and had
to pull a patch out this would you know
move you to the next patch cycle and it
became pretty clear that having such a
complicated build and branching system
was making it more difficult
to release security patches can you tell
us what was actually going on there I
mean I'm just trying to understand what
the situation actually looks like why
they were failing yeah unfortunately I
only know what they told me so my
understanding is that they had a few
core libraries that a lot of different
products used and that this change was
in one of those and then because that
change affects so many different
products it was possible to break things
sorry I just I just messed changing the
dependency pretty much yeah that it
seems like they must have messed up
their change somehow yeah with some
strange dependency issue but like what I
thought was surprising here was um the
person I talked to was just complaining
about the sheer number and also the
amount of time it takes to realize that
something has failed can you think of
some ways on how you were proposed like
minimal skills and branches and a large
project where say a hundred engineers
are working on the same code base yeah
so that can be challenging and as I said
I don't think that the dev branches are
a problem that's a fairly typical dev
process but I think where you really
have the problem is providing say
different branches to different
customers that you have to maintain for
a long period of time and what I think
the most important thing here is to just
realize the true cost of it I mean if
there's a really big customer that's
paying a lot maybe it's worth doing but
a lot of the vendors I worked with it
was something they did haphazardly
without really realizing that you do
this once for one customer it's fine you
do it a thousand times for a thousand
customers now you have to manually put
every you know patch into a thousand
trees yeah it's a huge overheat that's
like everything else I think you need to
understand the cost of it and in
particular things like branching and
build systems I feel like they often get
put off to another day even though
they're costing a lot of dev time and
quality and I think it's important to
make these things a priority yeah yeah
and the technical details up yeah you've
talked a little bit about our pruning
trees regularly and I'm making sure
code has an owner can you explain what
you mean by this yes these two things go
together by pruning trees I mean just
make sure all the code that is there is
in use because it's not uncommon
especially if code doesn't have owners
that there's this old feature that no
one has ever used that has bugs in it
and this is even a frequent method that
people use to find vulnerabilities
you'll look at code that hasn't been
updated recently because quite often you
know that code that was written before
we knew a lot about how vulnerabilities
worked and it's less likely that someone
has already found bones in it so that's
that's one problem and then making sure
code has an owner is just one way to
solve this it's good for security in
that if you have a problem it's always
good that all code as an owner because
we have had vendors get back to us and
say oh you know we don't think we can
fix this bug because we can't find who's
responsible for the code and that's a
very bad problem to have in an emergency
but also the joke I always make is if
someone owns code someone wants to get
rid of that code and no longer maintain
it and I find that can make dead code
get removed a lot more quickly yeah it's
it's it's surprisingly common that
doesn't know especially when defects
arise yeah I so what recommendations do
you have for reducing the chances of
introducing defects due to branching and
merging do you have any other ideas of
thoughts that we haven't covered yeah I
guess other than don't do it I don't
have a ton of advice I guess so one
thing that does help is good testing and
that's how we ended up resolving that
Android issue unfortunately like is
threw in a lot of situations it wasn't
realistic to reduce these branches
immediately but it is it was possible to
add a test for every branch and make
sure it gets run on every branch and
this is another problem that comes up
that sometimes what will find a bug in
something and find out that the
there you know has only been say testing
their new branch but not the old one or
you know ones that you know goes out in
one locale or not in other I'm so making
sure you have really robust testing for
every branch can sort of save you from
having tons of branches sometimes yeah
so we're just gonna move into a section
I'm on defects keen to talk about some
the CVE 2017 three five five eight
that's the memory corruption issue and
VirtualBox I'm allowing a guest to host
escalation now you mentioned this was
due to old code not being fully removed
it was a fixed upstream but not
downstream can you talk a bit about this
yes so yon horn on my team found that
bug and yeah basically it was due to two
problems one was that this bug had been
fixed up stream and not downstream and
since we were just talking about
branches yeah this is another risk that
you just forget to fix a bug and that's
what's what happened here that someone
had branched this code and not fixed it
but then the other slightly amusing
thing was that there was a to do they're
saying to remove the code but
unfortunately it didn't get to done and
this led to the bug so you know just a
reminder to make these sort of things a
priority thinking about removing the
code that doesn't help you need to
actually do it or attackers can use it
yeah that's actually quite common the
branch that you're talking about was
that a release branch or a development
branch I think it was a release branch
basically a different product pulled in
this code and didn't keep it up-to-date
so can we talk a bit about how the CVE
2015 seven eight nine four that's the
seven memory corruption issues in the
Samsung s6 edge image processing so this
was due to old no longer how used code
being left in a system yeah can we talk
a bit of it that was the bug I mentioned
earlier where they had the image
processor for the splash screen but they
made it available everywhere they
processed images and yeah that that made
this bug way way worse than it had to be
so um what could we have done
what could have done I'm sorry that this
didn't happen this is one where there's
a simple solution which is they could
have put that image decoder somewhere
where it only processed the splash
screen because that's highly privileged
code and if you can change that image
you know you already have very high
access to the device so that bug itself
wasn't the problem I think if they
changed it so that you know they just
loaded that image decoder in the boot
software and nowhere else they would
have solved this problem completely yeah
so so why was it put in other places as
well do you know no I don't my guess is
simplicity okay so you mentioned that
you know the following bugs were in the
JavaScript engines not the language
script can you tell us a bit about the
array dot species bug that C CVA 2016
7200 that's the issue with array dot
filter in M usage okay
so I've actually found a number of
issues in array dot species and just to
give a quick background on what array
dot species is in JavaScript you can
call a lot of methods on an array so you
can call like array dot splice in array
dot filter and the question is so all of
these return an array so if you call
this on a subclass of an array you get
an array back or you get the subclass of
an array back and array dot species
tries to solve this problem by I'm
allowing you to override this species
symbols to allow you to provide the
constructor that will create the thing
that is returned by all these array
functions so that's a fairly complicated
functionality and it's led to many
vulnerabilities including this array dot
filter vulnerability the problem is if
you think about JavaScript there's kind
of the objects in JavaScript and then
there's the engine that is written in
C++ and that has to take the objects
from JavaScript and manipulate them and
they don't always look the same under
the hood so most arrays work so that you
know an array starts its life in
JavaScript and you put an integer in it
and then it's an integer array and then
you put you know an object in it then it
becomes an object array
that is a lot bigger because objects are
pointers so they're twice as wide as
integers and then it can get even more
complicated for example you can make an
array read-only or you can make an
element of an array read-only and
basically the more complicated an array
is the bigger it is in memory so arrays
can get promoted to different types as
things happen to them and what happened
with array symbol species is because
you're adding this call to this
constructor in the middle of all these
sensitive array functions they can cause
a ray promotion to happen at unexpected
times so I think this array filter issue
it's originally an object array and then
you return an integer array and then
that becomes type confusion you can read
out the pointers as integers and I think
it's also an overflow because the
pointers are wider than the integers but
this happened time and time again with
this feature where basically you call it
it changes the array and the developer
didn't expect that that would happen
had an exhibit itself as before the
engineer I'm actually writing code on
top of it I mean what happened for them
what did they see yeah so this is one of
those bugs where you know you go to the
website and it executes code so you know
if you saw this issue without an exploit
would just look like a crash to you you
would use this code and yeah you'd get
like a segfault or something like that
but it's something that if a malicious
developer uses it they can make that
execute code so how did that actually
work can you give us a bit more details
on how you get it to execute your
arbitrary code sure so there's there's a
few different ways you can do this
depending on where the memory corruption
is but the general concept is that when
you can corrupt memory you can corrupt
things like pointers and you can change
where they point and sometimes you can
even change a pointer to code and make
it execute different code so that they
have a lot of different features in the
memory management of devices these days
that make this a lot more difficult but
still with a lot of effort you can make
it so that by corrupting memory in a
very crafted way you overwrite something
usually in many different state
ages that will eventually lead to a
pointer to code that you specify being
executed yeah cool so so what was the
array and x-axis of bag this that was
the CVA 2007 in two four four seven and
safari's function bind yeah that's
that's another interesting bug and this
is another very vulnerable JavaScript
feature and this is what I'm getting at
about this attack surface reduction
these are two JavaScript features that I
would say don't make JavaScript that
much better to end users that led to a
very large number of vulnerabilities and
and this one is that believe it or not
in JavaScript you can put an accessor so
a getter or a setter on an array index
so you can say you know array Sub Zero
and that'll execute execute JavaScript
and but what's even weirder is there's
this thing called prototypes in
JavaScript and this is basically
JavaScript inheritance and if it doesn't
find a property it'll go up to the
prototype and check its properties so
you can even add this on an array that
doesn't exist yet you can put this
getter or setter on the prototype and
then create an array and then for a
completely empty array do you know a Sub
Zero and that'll execute JavaScript so
this specific Safari bug this was just
unexpected behavior by the JavaScript
engine developer so what happened is in
this function bind which is a function
that will basically put default
parameters on a function so you call
bind and it creates this internal array
that holds these default parameters but
the engine developer didn't expect that
one that create when they create this
default array it could have a getter or
setter on it from the prototype so
that's what happens and then you get a
reference to this array that the
developer didn't think you could access
and then basically you can change the
length unexpectedly and it'll go out of
bounds so what about the typed array dot
sort defect and a message it was the CVE
216 seven - this is another feature
that's been
fairly error-prone and it's something
this is kind of even before I started
looking at JavaScript and many other
people found a lot of vulnerabilities in
this feature although to say something
about it I would say it is a very
heavily used and quite useful feature so
the typed arrays are arrays that can
hold integers and that sort of thing and
contiguous memory in JavaScript and
they're often used for performance
reasons because you know unlike arrays
that support array promotion you can
guarantee certain widths and stuff like
that and that as big performance
benefits but they also have this feature
detachment which basically frees the
memory and makes the pointer to the
array be null and there's been a lot of
problems with this especially if you
think about how javascript is not typed
this means if say you call typed array
of sort which happened in this case you
have to provide I think like an index
you start at and then there's also a
function that gets called to compare
stuff and then I think you know what one
of these could call the detach function
and then that caused the memory to be
freed and then you ended up sorting the
freed memory and this one's also
interesting in that it was a bug in the
standard so I read through the ACMA
script standard which is for JavaScript
and it was true that this check was
actually missing from the standard so
they wrote it exactly as it was
specified and the memory was freed and
liked and that's exactly what it said so
now the standards been fixed so it does
say you need to put an additional check
that the memory hasn't been freed before
you sort it all right so it's like the
most expensive place you can introduce
the defectors in your architecture and
the specification yeah it's true
you'd be surprised at how big an impact
the specification has on JavaScript
there's this bug and then there's these
two features that represent a very high
proportion of bugs and JavaScript and
they even have low usage so this is just
one example of how if you start early
and you know think about your features
they could have prevented a lot of bugs
yeah yes yeah pretty much what covers my
next question which was a
you mentioned in one of your talks that
standards can lead to security issues
yeah I mean that sounds a little
defeatist standards can also lead to a
lot of security improvements but yeah I
think like everything else on the
designs phase is crucial and deciding
what features are worthwhile and how
they're gonna be designed can determine
whether or not there are vulnerabilities
so it's important to keep your feature
as small and simple right from the
beginning and only do one thing I guess
I'm not against complex features it's
just that these two things especially
that array species which was fairly
difficult to describe and when you you
think about it you're like when am I
ever gonna use that and I think it's
like that sort of thing that can really
be avoided yeah no use code so if there
was only one thing you could say to
Aryan engineers today what would it be
yeah I guess just think about your
attack surface you've all heard the joke
oh it's not a bug it's a feature but
realize that bugs and features are
inextricably linked every bug starts its
life as features so if you can start by
designing your feature as well and
making sure that they're simple you can
do a lot to improve the security of your
software you don't try and be too
complicated with your code that you
write yeah do you have any interesting
personal projects or events on the go
currently so I guess I'm continuing to
look at browsers I've currently moved
away from JavaScript for the time being
and I'm looking into the new features
like web assembly and web RTC and I
think that's pretty cool and I would go
as far to say that I think web assembly
has done well so far with regards to
keeping their feature set small and
fairly simple and as a result I actually
didn't find that many bugs in it yeah so
so we had a show on now we were seemly I
think was just the previous show okay
so thanks for joining us today in Italy
it's been educational and fun well thank
you for software engineering radio this
was kim cada
thanks for listening to se Radio an
educational program brought to you by
Archer police software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SE - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com
you can also email us at team @ SC -
radio net this and all other episodes of
se radio is licensed under Creative
Commons license 2.5 thanks for listening